Jack Milgrom Papers
Jack Milgrom Papers
- Research files
  - Recycling: deposit state experiences, 1981-2003; brochures, pamphlets, newsletters, and articles (Box 17)
  - Terex: MSW system executive summary, undated; report by Terex Corporation about municipal solid waste as containing recoverable resources (Box 17)
  - Terex: WRI, 1994-1995; communications, invoices, and reports related to dealings with Walden Research, Inc (Box 17)
  - Terex: miscellaneous, 1994-1998 (Box 17)
    Includes: Contract with MGA Southern Africa, press releases, diagrams, notes, "Ammonia fiber explosion (AFEX) pretreatment of municipal solid waste" report, "Comprehensive waste recovery system" packet.
  - Utility: Alcan Cable, 1989-1991; catalog of investor-owned electric utility companies operating in the United States (30th edition) and an assortment of communications, notes, memos, and clippings (Box 17)
  - Utility: Alcan Cable, 1991; notes, meeting agenda, meeting minutes, e-mail, and part of a report (Box 17)
  - Utility: Alcatel Canada Wire and Cable, 1992; brochures, communications and notes (Box 17)
  - Utility: Baltimore Gas and Electric, 1990-1991; brochures, communications and notes (Box 17)
  - Utility: Cleveland Electric, 1990; notes, letters, an annual report (Box 17)
  - Utility: Detroit Edison, 1990-1991; letters, notes, and an annual report (Box 17)
  - Utility: Florida Power and Light, 1982; 1990-1991; letters and notes (Box 18)
  - Utility: General Public Utilities, 1991; letters, requests for proposals, brochure, and notes (Box 18)
  - Utility: Leaversuch papers, 1991; 1994,; 1996; letters, newsletter, data sheets, and clippings (Box 18)
  - Utility: Ohio Edison, 1989-1991; notes, letter, and an annual report (Box 18)
  - Utility: Southwire, 1991-1992; letters, notes, reports (Box 18)
  - Utility: Sumitomo, 1999; includes a single letter from Milgrom to Sumitomo inquiring about recycling process (Box 18)
  - Utility: Wire Choppers, 1997-2003; letters, notes, directions, and clippings (Box 18)
  - Utility: miscellaneous, 1990-2003; letters, notes, clippings, and brochures (Box 18)
- Writings
  - Changing food and beverage packaging markets: The drive for convenience and environmental responsibility, 1991; 2 copies of the report and the executive summary (Box 18)
  - Competitive trends in packaging: Dynamic technology changes within a mature industry, 1983-1984; 3 copies of the report and 5 copies of the executive summary (Box 18)
  - Degradable plastics report, 1989; aso includes a clipping of "Biofoam: Snacks to loose fill" and two handwritten notes (Box 18)
  - Homogenous reactions catalyzed by platinum, 1959-1960; Also includes a draft and related memorandum (Box 18)
  - Identifying the nuisance plastics, 1973; an article printed in New Scientist (Box 18)
  - Intermaterial competition in beverage packaging, 1990; 2 copies (Box 18)
  - Methylnaphthalene complexes, 1958; 1966 (Box 19)
    2 copies of Methyl naphthalene complexes, Metal-Olefin Complexes (internal memorandum), Ethers of olefin alcohols (clipping), and part of a journal article from Journal of Polymer Science, Part A-2, Vol. 4
  - Overview of PET bottle recycling, 1984; speech presented at the Eighth International Conference on Oriented Plastics Containers (Box 19)
  - Overview of plastics recycling, 1981-1982; 2 versions: a photocopied book chapter and a speech (2 copies) (Box 19)
  - Platinum (II), 1959; 2 copies, drafts, and preparatory notes (Box 19)
  - Preliminary survey of novel fabrication technology for plastics and elastomers, 1982; prepared for C. ITOC & Co. in Tokyo (Box 19)
  - Program to promote PET beverage bottle recycling in non-deposit states, 1984; report to Coca-Cola USA by Milgrom, on behalf of Walden Research Institute (Box 19)
  - Resource recovery and energy review Articles, 1975; 2 articles from Resource Recovery and Energy Review: "Recovery of glass from municipal wastes" (in Mar/Apr 1975) (2 copies and 1 photocopy), "Does too much plastic go to waste?" (in Jul/Aug 1975) (1 copy and 1 photocopy) (Box 19)
  - Single-service beer and soft drink container market: Capacity, production, and outlook, 1989; co-written with Zachary Tahmin (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous, 1993-1995 (Box 19)
    Includes: Reclaiming Single Plastic Resins: Tracking Technology Developments (article in Spectrum) (2 copies), Trends and Opportunities in Plastics Recycling in the United States (article in Decision Resources) (2 copies), An Overview of the Markets for Recycled Plastics (article in Polymer Recycling, Vol. 1, No. 4) (15 copies), Recycling Plastics: Current Status (from Conservation andi Recycling Vol 3), newspaper clippings, Packaging and the Environment (article in Cereal Foods World, Vol. 31, No. 11).